Guide to the William A. Speck Collection of Goetheana: Medals and Medallions
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
William A. Speck collection of Goetheana: medals and medallions
1740-1934
YCGL MSS 28
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
6
(23 boxes)
The William A. Speck Collection of Goetheana: Medals and Medallions consists of 178 medals, coins, medallions, and reliefs depicting Johann Wolfgang von Goethe, Friedrich Schiller, and other figures, mostly literary. By date, the pieces range from 1740 (a Gutenberg medal commemorating the tercentennial of the invention of printing) to 1934. The earliest Goethe items are a circa 1775 tin medal by Boltschauser and an 1808 medallion modeled by the painter Gerhard Kügelgen (1772-1820). Many medals and medallions date from anniversaries, especially from Goethe's centenary in 1849 and his subsequent birth and death anniversaries in 1899 and 1932. Several Schiller medals commemorate the centenary of his birth in 1859 and the hundredth anniversary of his death in 1905.
Speck, William A. (William Alfred), 1864-1928
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired at various times and from various sources.
Custodial History
Commemorative medals and medallions featuring images of Goethe and Schiller were one of the earliest collecting interests of William A. Speck, founder and first curator of the Speck Collection of Goetheana. Correspondence preserved in Speck's papers indicate that he was purchasing Goethe coins and medals as early as 1890 from dealers in Germany and the United States, among them Adolf E.Cahn and L.& L. Hamburger, both in Frankfurt a.M.; Carl Wiebe in Hamburg; and in New York City, Edward Frossard. When the Speck Collection was acquired by Yale in 1913, the university's press release noted that it included a "practically complete collection of medals struck in his [Goethe's] honor."
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Associated Materials
Associated Materials: William A. Speck Collection of Goetheana: Manuscripts (YCGL MSS 6), William A. Speck Collection of Goetheana: Music (YCGL MSS 9), and William A. Speck Collection of Prints (YCGL MSS 11), William A. Speck collection of Goetheana: Theater Ephemera (YCGL MSS 24), William A. Speck Collection of Goetheana: Original Artwork (YCGL MSS 26), and William A. Speck Collection of Goetheana: General Ephemera (YCGL MSS 27), Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library.
William A. Speck (1864-1928)
William A. Speck, the son of German immigrants, was born in New York City in 1864. A pharmacist by profession, he amassed the largest Goethe collection outside of Germany. In 1913, he and his collection came from Haverstraw, New York to Yale, where he served as curator of the Speck Collection until his death in 1928. For further biographical information on William A. Speck and a general history and description of the Speck Collection, see the finding aid for the William A. Speck Collection of Goetheana: Manuscripts (YCGL MSS 6).
Scope and Contents
The William A. Speck Collection of Goetheana: Medals and Medallions consists of 178 medals, coins, medallions, and reliefs depicting Johann Wolfgang von Goethe, Friedrich Schiller, and other figures, mostly literary. By date, the pieces range from 1740 (a Gutenberg medal commemorating the tercentennial of the invention of printing) to 1934. The earliest Goethe items are the circa 1775 tin medal by Boltschauser and the 1808 medallion modeled by the painter Gerhard Kügelgen (1772-1820). The medals and medallions tend to cluster around anniversary dates: Goethe's centenary in 1849 and his subsequent birth and death anniversaries in 1899 and 1932. Several Schiller medals commemorate the centenary of his birth in 1859 and the hundredth anniversary of his death in 1905.
This collection was featured in the lead article, with a supplemental loose plate, in the second issue of The Yale University Library Gazette (I:2, October 1926). In this essay, entitled "The Goethe Medals and Medallions in Yale University Library," Speck states that the collection includes all but one of the Goethe medals modeled from life. He then tells the story of one of the rarest items in the collection, the discarded jubilee medal of 1826. The Swiss medalist Henri François Brandt (1789-1845), who spent most of his professional life in Berlin, was commissioned by Duke Carl August of Saxe-Weimar to create a medal commemorating the fiftieth anniversary of Goethe's residency in Weimar. The obverse showed Goethe in profile, the reverse Carl August and his wife Luise. But the duke was dissatisfied with this first strike, disliking his own portrait and the horn-like curls the artist gave to Luise. A new medal was made, in which the offending curls were deleted and Goethe became slimmer. Both versions are included in the collection.
The collection contents list notes the depictions on the obverse/reverse of each item, the material from which it is made, the creator of the medal, and any notes.
Arrangement
Organized into five series: I. Medals and Reliefs Depicting Goethe. II. Medals and Reliefs Depicting Schiller. III. Medals and Reliefs Depicting other figures. IV. Larger Medallions and Reliefs. V. Similar Objects Made of Non-metallic Materials.
Authors, German; German literature -- 18th century; German literature -- 19th century; Coins (money); Plaques (flat objects); Medals; Medallions (medals); Reliefs (sculptures); Souvenirs; Authors -- Germany -- 18th century; Authors -- Germany -- 19th century; Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von, 1749-1832; Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von, 1749-1832 -- Portraits; Schiller, Friedrich, 1759-1805; Schiller, Friedrich, 1759-1805 -- Portraits; Speck, William A. (William Alfred), 1864-1928
- Medals and Reliefs Depicting Goethe, 1808-1932; Series I; (84 items)
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Goethe/eagle, tin medal. By Hans Heinrich Boltschauser, after a plaster relief made around the same time by Johann Peter Melchior., circa 1775; 1 5/8 inches (Box 21, Folder 151)
    Scope and Contents
    From envelope 16
  - Goethe, iron relief medal. By Gerhard von Kügelgen, 1808; 3 3/4 inches (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    From envelope 10
  - Goethe/Pegasus, bronze medal. By Johann Gottfried Schadow. "One of the few original bronze casts", 1816; 3 5/8 inches (Box 1, Folder 2)
    From envelope 11
  - Goethe/Pegasus, iron medal. By Johann Gottfried Schadow. Later casting in iron, 1816; 3 3/4 inches (Box 1, Folder 3)
    From envelope 12
  - Goethe/eagle, bronze medal. By Jean François Antoine Bovy, 1824; 1 1/2 inches (Box 1, Folder 4)
    From envelope 9
  - Goethe/relief - no image, iron medal. By Jean François Antoine Bovy. Sample strike of above?, circa 1824; 1 5/8 inches (Box 1, Folder 5)
    From envelope 70
  - Goethe/blank, silver medal. By Henri François Brandt. Sample strike, circa 1825; 1 1/2 inches (Box 1, Folder 6)
    From envelope 2
  - Goethe/ Karl August and Luise, bronze medal. By Henri François Brandt. "Rejected Jubilee Medal". Two copies., 1825; 1 1/2 inches, 2 items (Box 1, Folder 7)
    From envelope 1
  - Goethe/ Karl August and Luise, medal. By Henri François Brandt. Official Jubilee Medal, 1825; 1 1/2 inches (Box 1, Folder 8)
    From envelope 3
  - Goethe/ Dem VII Nov MDCCCXXV, bronze and pewter medals. By Angelika Facius. Jubilee of Goethe's arrival in Weimar, 1825; 1 1/2 inches, 2 items (Box 1, Folder 9)
    From envelope 4
  - Goethe/Goethe being crowned with laurel. By Friedrich Anton König. Later strike? Edge: Loos Foundery, Berlin, 1826; 1 5/8 inches (Box 1, Folder 10)
    From envelope 13
  - Goethe/Goethe being crowned with laurel, bronze medal. By Friedrich Anton König, 1826; 1 5/8 inches (Box 1, Folder 11)
    From envelope 19
  - Goethe/ Goethe being crowned, iron medal. By Friedrich Anton König, 1826; 1 5/8 inches (Box 1, Folder 12)
    From envelope 71
  - Goethe, relief medal. By Leonard Posch., 1827; 3 1/2 inches (Box 2, Folder 13)
    From envelope 14
  - Goethe, iron relief medal. By Johann Carl Fischer., 1827; 4 inches (Box 2, Folder 14)
    From envelope 18
  - Goethe/Janus, bronze medal. By Jean François Antoine Bovy, 1831; 1 5/8 inches (Box 2, Folder 15)
    From envelope 17
  - Goethe/text, medal commemorating Goethe's death. By H. Wilke, 1832; 1 1/2 inches (Box 2, Folder 16)
    From envelope 5
  - Goethe/poet borne aloft on a swan, two medals commemorating Goethe's death. By Friedrich Anton König, 1832; 1 5/8 inches, 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    From envelope 6
  - Goethe/ poet borne aloft on a swan. By Friedrich Anton König. Combines obverse of 1826 medal and reverse of the preceeding, 1832; 1 5/8 inches (Box 2, Folder 18)
    From envelope 7
  - Goethe/blank, lead medal. By Friedrich Anton König. Possibly a sample strike, 1832; 1 5/8 inches (Box 2, Folder 19)
    From envelope 72
  - Goethe/text. By Wilhelm Kullrich. On reverse: "Zur Erinnerung an den 28 August 1849", 1 1/2 inches (Box 2, Folder 20)
    From envelope 20
  - Schiller & Goethe/text, pewter medal. By Wilke. On reverse: "Den deutschen Dichter Heroen", 1860; 1 1/2 inches (Box 2, Folder 21)
    From envelope 15
  - Goethe/text. By Lauer (?) Issued by Goethe-Garten, Blasewitz, 1881; 7/8 inch (Box 2, Folder 22)
    From envelope 95
  - Goethe/ mythological poetry and truth, bronze medal. By Hugo Kaufmann. City of Frankfurt medal commemorating Goethes birth, 1899; 2 1/2 inches (Box 2, Folder 23)
    From envelope 31
  - Goethe/Frankfurt Goethehaus, bronze medal. By Oscar Bergmann, 1899; 1 1/2 inches (Box 2, Folder 24)
    From envelope 33
  - Goethe/heraldic device. By Jörgum & Trefz, 1899; 1 5/8 inches (Box 3, Folder 25)
    From envelope 34
  - Goethe and six women/Goethe bust, bronze medal. By Josef Kowarzik, 1899; 5 1/2 inches, obl. (Box 3, Folder 26)
    From envelope 41
  - Goethe/outdoor scene, bronze medal. By Josef Kowarzik. Reverse shows figure walking, surrounded by phantom figures, 1899; 2 /14 inches, rect. (Box 3, Folder 27)
    From envelope 43
  - Goethe/ Goethe house in Frankfurt, silver medal. By L. C. Lauer, 1899; 2 inches (Box 3, Folder 28)
    From envelope 45
  - Goethe receiving laurel crown/Frankfurt Goethehaus, two copies of different medals. By Heinrich Oppenheim, 1899; 1 5/8 inches, 2 items (Box 3, Folder 29)
    From envelope 46
  - Goethe/heavenly scene. By Anton Scharff. On reverse: depiction of Prolog im Himmel from Faust I?, 1899; 2 5/8 inches (Box 3, Folder 30)
    From envelope 47
  - Goethe/Frankfurt Goethe house. By Lauer, 1899; 1 inch (Box 3, Folder 31)
    From envelope 69
  - Goethe/Frankfurt Goethehaus, profile, bronze medal. By Rudolf Bosselt., 1899; 3 inches (Box 3, Folder 32)
    From envelope 48
  - Goethe/text, Masonic emblem, aluminum medal. By Johann von Langa (?) Issued by Loge Amalia, Weimar, 1899; 1 3/4 inches (Box 3, Folder 33)
    From envelope 73
  - Goethe/blank, silver alloy medal. By Lauer. Two copies, one in relief (test strike?), 1899; 2 1/8 inches, rect., 2 items (Box 3, Folder 34)
    From envelope 74
  - Goethe monument/text. By Jörgum & Trefz. Two copies, 1899; 1 1/8 inches, 2 items (Box 3, Folder 35)
    From envelope 75
  - Goethe/wreath and text, copper medal., 1899; 1 1/4 inches (Box 4, Folder 36)
    From envelope 76
  - Goethe/wreath and text, bronze medal. By Lauer, 1899; 1 1/8 inches (Box 4, Folder 37)
    From envelope 77
  - Goethe/Gartenhaus, Weimar. Two copies, one on aluminum(?), 1899; 1 1/2 inches, 2 items (Box 4, Folder 38)
    From envelope 78
  - Goethe monument/wreath and text. Attached to fringed ribbon and pin, 1899; 1 1/8 inches (Box 4, Folder 39)
    From envelope 79
  - Goethe/Frankfurt Goethe house. Attached to fringed ribbon and pin, 1899; 1 1/2 inches (Box 4, Folder 40)
    From envelope 80
  - Goethe monument/Frankfurt Goethe house, bronze medal. By Jörgum & Trefz. With smaller example, 1 1/4 inches; with cheaper copy of each size hung on ribbons, 1899; 1 1/2 inches, 2 items; 1 1/4 inches, 2 items (Box 4, Folder 41-41a)
    From envelope 87
  - Nude youth viewing Goethe monument/blank, bronze medal. By Rudolph Ferdinand Marschall. Inaugurations of Vienna Goethe monument, 1900; 3 inches, rect. (Box 4, Folder 42)
    From envelope 50
  - Katharina Elisabeth Goethe/ family scene, bronze medal. By Rudolf Bosselt. Plaquette honoring Goethe's mother, 1902; 2 /14 inches, rect. (Box 4, Folder 43)
    From envelope 40
  - Goethe, Schiller/ Frankfurt theater. By Heinrich Oppenheim. Celebrates opening of the new theater, 1902; 1 1/2 inches (Box 4, Folder 44)
    From envelope 42
  - Goethe's mother/Frankfurt scene, silver medal. By Hugo Kaufmann. Centenary of the Musterschule in Frankfurt, 1903; 1 inch (Box 4, Folder 45)
    From envelope 94
  - Goethe and Schiller/quotation & emblem, bronze/silver alloy medal. By Mayer & Wilhelm, Stuttgart. Issued by Loge Amalia, Weimar, 1905; 2 inches (Box 4, Folder 46)
    From envelope 92
  - Bezirksverein deutscher Ingenieure/Goethe quote, copper/brass alloy medal. By Rudolf Bosselt, 1913; 1 3/4 inches (Box 5, Folder 47)
    From envelope 81
  - Goethe/text in English, bronze medal. Bovy (reproduction). Award from Carl Schurz Foundation for best essay, 1932; 1 5/8 inches (Box 5, Folder 48)
    From envelope 35
  - Goethe/ torchbearer, bronze medal. By Fritz Grosshans. Issued in Newark, New Jersey, 1932; 2 3/4 inches (Box 5, Folder 49)
    From envelope 38
  - Goethe/Goethe Gedenkjahr 1932, 1 1/4 inches (Box 5, Folder 50)
    From envelope 82
  - Goethe/nude woman, iron medal. By Wilhelm Oskar Prack., [19??]; 2 1/8 inches (Box 5, Folder 51)
    From envelope 52
  - Goethe/blank, in box with NYC shop address, [19??]; 3 3/8 inches, rect. (Box 5, Folder 52)
    From envelope 66
  - Goethe/blank, bronze medal, attached stand on back, has exhibition label. By Stiasny, [19??]; 2 1/2 inches, rect. (Box 5, Folder 53)
    From envelope 67
  - Goethe/ scene from Faust? By Rudolf Mayer., [19??]; 2 1/4 inches (Box 5, Folder 54)
    From envelope 36
  - Goethe/ Mehr Licht, goldbronze medal. By Johann Schwertner. Issued by Loge Goethe, Pressburg, undated; 1 1/2 inches (Box 5, Folder 55)
    From envelope 44
  - Goethe/blank, bronze medal. By C. Müller, undated; 3 3/4 inches (Box 5, Folder 56)
    From envelope 65
  - Goethe/blank, medal after Bovy. Carnelian glass intaglio, with 2 other small cameos, undated; 1 1/4 inches, rect., and smaller: 3 items (Box 6, Folder 57)
    From envelope 68
  - Goethe/blank, bronze medal. By Mayer & Wilhelm, Stuttg., undated; 1 3/4 inches, rect. (Box 6, Folder 58)
    From envelope 83
  - Goethe/woman with lyre and laurel wreath. By Mayer & Wilhelm, Stuttg., undated; 2 inches, 2 items (Box 6, Folder 59)
    From envelope 84
  - Goethe and Schiller/shield bronze medal and silver alloy medal. By Mayer & Wilhelm, Stuttg., undated; 2 inches, 2 items (Box 6, Folder 60)
    From envelope 85
  - Goethe/ Goethe and Schiller, medals. By Mayer & Wilhelm, Stuttg., undated; 2 inches, 2 items (Box 6, Folder 61)
    From envelope 86
  - Goethe house in relief, undated; 1 inch (Box 6, Folder 62)
    From envelope 88
  - Goethe in relief, undated; 5/8 inch (Box 6, Folder 63)
    From envelope 89
  - Goethe/blank, undated; 1 inch (Box 6, Folder 64)
    From envelope 90
  - Goethe/blank, undated; 2 1/4 inches, rect. (Box 6, Folder 65)
    From envelope 91
  - Goethe/wreath and text, copper medal. Lauer. "Spielpfennig" - two examples, reverse different, undated; 7/8 inch, 2 items (Box 6, Folder 66)
    From envelope 93
  - Goethe. Sample cast?, undated; 1 5/8 inches (Box 6, Folder 67)
    From envelope 133
- Medals and Reliefs Depicting Schiller, 1819-1905; Series II; (33 items)
  - Schiller/text, bronze medal. By Jean Jacques Barre., 1819; 1 5/8 inches (Box 7, Folder 68)
    From envelope 96
  - Schiller/Schiller's house in Weimar, bronze medal. By Angelika Facius, 1847; 1 5/8 inches (Box 7, Folder 69)
    From envelope 97
  - Schiller/text, tombak medal. By Wenzel Seidan. Issued by the Prague Schiller Verein, 1859; 1 inch (Box 7, Folder 70)
    From envelope 98
  - Schiller/den 20 November 1859, pewter medal, after Barre. Issued by the Maschinenbaugesellschaft, Karlsruhe, 1 5/8 inches (Box 7, Folder 71)
    From envelope 99
  - Schiller/ Muse with wings and lyre, bronze medal. By Fischer & Staudigel, 1859; 1 5/8 inches (Box 7, Folder 72)
    From envelope 100
  - Schiller/Lied von der Glocke. By Staudigel & Schnitzspahn. Commemorating the centenary of his birth, 1859; 1 5/8 inches (Box 7, Folder 73)
    From envelope 51
  - Schiller/Calliope on an eagle, bronze medal. By Carl Radnitzky. Centenary festival at Vienna, 1859; 1 inch (Box 7, Folder 74)
    From envelope 102
  - Schiller/wreath and text, bronze medal. By Wilhelm Kullrich. Centenary celebration in Berlin, 1859; 1 1/2 inches (Box 7, Folder 75)
    From envelope 103
  - Schiller/lyre, bronze medal. By Sebald & Drentwett, 1859; 1 1/2 inches (Box 7, Folder 76)
    From envelope 104
  - Schiller/Lied von der Glocke, bronze medal. By Fritz Staudigel. Notes say collection included copy in gold, 1859; 1 5/8 inches (Box 7, Folder 77)
    From envelope105
  - Schiller/text, bronze plated medal. By H. Wilke, 1859; 1 1/8 inches (Box 7, Folder 78)
    From envelope 106
  - Schiller/wreath and text, tin medal. By A. Kerwien, issued in New York, text in German., 1859; 1 5/8 inches (Box 7, Folder 79)
    From envelope 107
  - Schiller/bell, bronze medal. By Allen & Moore, Birmingham, [1859?]; 2 inches (Box 7, Folder 80)
    From envelope 101
  - Schiller/text, bronze and pewter medals. Issued in New York, text in English, 1859; 1 5/8 inches, 2 items (Box 21, Folder 152)
    From envelope 108
  - Female figure with lyre/Schiller momument.By Carl Radnitzky. Unveiling of Schiller momument in Vienna, 1876; 2 1/8 inches (Box 7, Folder 81)
    From envelope 109
  - Schiller/text, silver medal. By Oscar Bergmann. 25th anniversary,Schiller Stiftung, Weimar, 1884; 1 1/8 inches (Box 8, Folder 82)
    From envelope 110
  - Schiller/wreath and text, silver medal. By Sebald & Drentwett. 15th anniversity, Deutsche Schiller-Stiftung, 1884; 1 1/2 inches (Box 8, Folder 83)
    From envelope 111
  - Goethe-Schiller monument/wreath & text, brass medal. By Lauer. Thüringisches Kreisturnfest, Weimar, 1887; 1 1/4 inches (Box 8, Folder 84)
    From envelope 112
  - Schiller/scene: Lied von der Glocke. By Rudolf Mayer. Similar to envelope 36 above, 1905; 2 1/4 inches (Box 8, Folder 85)
    From envelope 49
  - Schiller/text, 1905; 1 1/8 inches (Box 8, Folder 86)
    From envelope 114
  - Schiller/blank, bronze medal. By Rudolf Mayer, 1905; 4 5/8 inches (Box 8, Folder 87)
    From envelope 61
  - Schiller/text and emblem, bronze medal. By Mayer & Wilhelm. Issued by Loge Amalia, Weimar, 1905; 2 inches (Box 8, Folder 88)
    From envelope 113
  - Schiller/wreath and bell, copper medal. By Lauer. "Spielpfennig", undated; 7/8 inch (Box 8, Folder 89)
    From envelope 119
  - Schiller/Muse with lyre. By Mayer & Wilhelm. Obverse same as envelope113. Copies in different metals, undated; 2 inches, 2 items (Box 8, Folder 90)
    From envelope 115
  - Schiller/blank, undated; 2 5/8 inches, rect. (Box 8, Folder 91)
    From envelope 116
  - Schiller/Schiller and Goethe. By Mayer & Wilhelm. Obverse same as envelope 113., undated; 2 inches (Box 8, Folder 92)
    From envelope 117
  - Schiller/lyre on a pedestal, bronze medal. By Friedrich Wilhelm Facius, undated; 1 3/8 inches (Box 8, Folder 93)
    From envelope 118
  - Schiller/text, silver and bronze medals. By Franz Apell. Commemorates Schiller's election to the Academie der gemeinnütziger Wissenschaften, Erfurt, in 1791, undated; 1 1/8 inches, 2 items (Box 9, Folder 94)
    From envelope 120
  - Schiller/ wreath and text, bronze medal. By Lauer., undated; 1 1/8 inches (Box 9, Folder 95)
    From envelope 121
  - Schiller/wreath and text, undated; 2 inches (Box 9, Folder 96)
    From envelope 122
- Medals and Reliefs Depicting Other People, 1740-1934; Series III; (30 items)
  Arranged alphabetically by name of subject.
  - Carl August/text, bronze medal. By Bertrand Andrieu. Reverse: Mitescunt aspera saecla, 1816; 1 1/2 inches (Box 9, Folder 97)
    From envelope 25
  - Carl August/wreath, bronze medal. By Henri François Brandt. Commemorates 50th anniversary of his reign, 1825; 1 5/8 inches (Box 9, Folder 98)
    From envelope 27
  - Carl August/zodiac, bronze medal. By Angelika Facius. Commemorates his death, 1828; 1 5/8 inches (Box 9, Folder 99)
    From envelope 28
  - Karl August/ Rietschel's Goethe/Schiller monument, bronze and silver medals. By Sebald - Drentwett. Commemorates the unveiling of the monument, 1857; 1 5/8 inches, 2 items (Box 9, Folder 100)
    From envelope 8 and envelope 21
  - Carl Alexander & Sophie/wreath and text, bronze medal. By Angelika Facius.Carl Alexander was grandson of Carl August; 25th wedding anniversary, 1867; 1 1/2 inches (Box 9, Folder 101)
    From envelope 32
  - Carl Friedrich/text, bronze medal. By Henrich Bubert. Reverse: Die Gemeinden des Eisenachischen Unterlands am 15 Juni 1853, 1 3/4 inches (Box 9, Folder 102)
    From envelope 22
  - Carl Gustav Carus/Psyche between day & night, bronze medal. By Ulbricht, 1847; 1 3/4 inches (Box 9, Folder 103)
    From envelope 123
  - Benjamin Constant/text, bronze medal. By François Augustin Caunois., 1827; 1 5/8 inches (Box 9, Folder 104)
    From envelope 124
  - Karl Wilhelm von Fritsch/wreath & text, bronze medal. By Angelika Facius, 1839; 1 5/8 inches (Box 9, Folder 105)
    From envelope 62
  - Christian F. Gellert/Calliope [?], silver medal. By J. H. Meil., [1769?]; 1 1/2 inches (Box 21, Folder 153)
    From envelope 59
  - Salomon Gessner/wreath, bronze medal. By Hans Heinrich Boltschauser., undated; 2 inches (Box 9, Folder 106)
    From envelope 57
  - Franz Grillparzer/lyre, bronze medal. By Anton Scharff. Commemorates unveiling of monument in Vienna, 1889; 2 1/4 inches (Box 10, Folder 107)
    From envelope 125
  - J. Gutenberg & J. Faust/text. 300th anniversary of invention of printing, 1740; 1 1/4 inches (Box 10, Folder 108)
    From envelope 126
  - J. G. Herder/wreath and text, bronze medal. By Angelika Facius. Unveiling of Herder Monument, Weimar, 1850; 1 5/8 inches (Box 10, Folder 109)
    From envelope 127
  - Alexander von Humboldt/text and wreath, bronze medal. By Carl Pfeuffer, undated; 1 5/8 inches (Box 10, Folder 110)
    From envelope 54
  - Alexander von Humboldt/Humboldt, seated, bronze medal. By Gottfried Bernhard Loos., 1805; 1 1/2 inches (Box 10, Folder 111)
    From envelope 60
  - F. H. Jacobi/text, silver medal. By Joseph Losch., 1819; 1 5/8 inches (Box 10, Folder 112)
    From envelope 128
  - Luise, Grand Duchess/text, bronze medal. By J. A. F. Bovy. Reverse: Das Gerettet Weimar MDCCCVI, 1826; 1 5/8 inches (Box 10, Folder 113)
    From envelope 23
  - Maria Pavlovna/text, bronze medal. By Angelika Facius. Commemorates 50th anniversary of her reign as Grand Duchess of Saxe-Weimar, 1854; 2 1/8 inches (Box 10, Folder 114)
    From envelope 30
  - Heinrich Meyer/text, silver medal. By Angelika Facius, 1833; 1 5/8 inches (Box 10, Folder 115)
    From envelope 63
  - Napoleon/insignia, bronze medal. By Louis Jaley. Comemmorates the creation of the Legion of Honor; obverse designed by Bertrand Andrieu, 1806; 1 5/8 inches (Box 10, Folder 116)
    From envelope 24
  - Walter Scott/female figure, bronze medal. By Thomas and Alfred J. Stothard, 1827; 2 3/8 inches (Box 10, Folder 117)
    From envelope 131
  - Madame de Staël/text, bronze medal. By Jacques Edouard Gatteaux., 1819; 1 5/8 inches (Box 10, Folder 118)
    From envelope 55
  - C. A. Tiedge/pegasus, bronze medal. By Söhnitz, undated; 1 1/2 inches (Box 10, Folder 119)
    From envelope 129
  - Christian Gottlob von Voigt/3 wreaths, bronze medal. By F. W. Facius, 1816; 1 1/4 inches (Box 10, Folder 120)
    From envelope 53